<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twinnims</title>
    <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Twinnims</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.twinnims.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twinnims Project</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:33:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>The idea behind the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 14:16:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/consortium/</guid>
      <description>Partners of the project with contact information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 14:18:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>People who oversight the project implementation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 14:22:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/publications/</guid>
      <description>Joined open publication of the participants</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alvo Aabloo</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/aabloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/aabloo/</guid>
      <description>  Professor, University of Tartu   Alvo Aabloo is in charge of Intelligent Materials and Systems Lab, the interdisciplinary research group established in 2003 in University of Tartu, Institute of Technology. His research intrests are involving computational materials science, polymer eletrolytes, ionic conductive materials, artificial muscles, soft sensors, polymer batteries, soft robotics, collaborative robotics, space technology.
 Email: alvo.aabloo@ut.ee Social neworks: linkedin Homepage: https://ims.ut.ee/User:Alvo ORCID: 0000-0002-0183-1282  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Cattan</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/cattan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/cattan/</guid>
      <description>Professor, UPHF Valenciennes, France   In 1993, he obtained a PhD in optics and photonics at the University of Paris Sud (Orsay), and in 1994, he became a University Lecturer and was assigned to the laboratory of Advanced Ceramic Materials, France. He was appointed University Professor in 2002 at UPHF Valenciennes, France, and was assigned to the Institute of Electronics, Microelectronics and Nanotechnology where he took over the management of a research group made up of thirteen professors and university lecturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indrek Must</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/must/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/must/</guid>
      <description>Associate professor, University of Tartu   He received a PhD degree in physical engineering in 2014 from UTARTU (Estonia), focusing on motion and humidity sensing properties of soft ionic electroactive laminates based on carbon-polymer composites. His work at UTARTU targeted matching of soft, ionic and capacitive artificial muscle technology to the requirements imposed by soft robotics, demonstrating the very first prototypes of one-gram-scale energy-autonomous soft robots propelled by artificial muscles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isabella Fiorello</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/fiorello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/fiorello/</guid>
      <description>PhD student, Center for Micro-BioRobotics (CMBR) of Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia (IIT), Pontedera, Italy   Isabella Fiorello is a PhD student in Biorobotics jointly at Scuola Superiore Sant&#39;Anna (SSSA) in Pisa and at the Center for Micro-BioRobotics (CMBR) of Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia (IIT) in Pontedera (Italy) under the supervision of the CMBR Director, Dr Barbara Mazzolai. She received a BSc in Molecular Biology in 2014 and a MSc in Industrial Biotechnology (with Honours) in 2017 from the University of Turin (Italy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Janno Torop</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/torop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/torop/</guid>
      <description>Researcher in Materials Science in the IMS lab, University of Tartu   Janno Torop received a PhD degree in physical engineering from University of Tartu in 2012. In spring 2013 he joined Biosensors and Bioelectronics Centre at Linköping University as postdoc. In 2015 he got a visiting researcher fellowship in Lappeenranta Technical University in Finland. His current research interests are related to electroactive film actuators and bioengineered sensor systems by combining porous carbon materials and conjugated polymers in order to improve energy efficiency during actuation cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaija Pohako-Esko</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/pohako-esko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/pohako-esko/</guid>
      <description>Research fellow of materials technology   Kaija Pohako-Esko received her PhD degree in organic chemistry from University of Tartu in 2013. After post-doc at University of Erlangen-Nuremberg, Germany, she joined the IMS Lab as reseacrh fellow of materials technology. Her research interests include ionic liquids, their synthesis, biocompatibility and toxicologigal aspects and usage of ionic liquids in smart multifunctional systems.
 Email: kaija.pohako@ut.ee Social networks: linkedin Homepage: https://ims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saoni Banerji</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/banerji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/banerji/</guid>
      <description>Research Fellow (CMOS-MEMS, microfabrication, microelectronic design)   She received her M.Sc. degree in electronics from Nanyang Technological University (NTU), Singapore, in 2014. Her dissertation focused on developing an ultrasonic IC link for wireless power and data transfer integrated with MEMS ultrasonic transducers for wireless medical devices implanted deep inside the patient’s body. She received a Ph.D. degree, with an FI AGAUR grant from Catalonian government, in the fields of microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) design and circuits and designing control architectures for MEMS sensors signal conditioning with the Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya, Barcelona, Spain in November, 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastien Grondel</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/grondel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/grondel/</guid>
      <description>Professor, UPHF Valenciennes, France   He received the M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in electronical and acoustical Engineering from Valenciennes University, France, in 1997 and 2000, respectively. Between 2001 and 2010, he worked as a research Associate at the Electronic, Microelectronic and Nanoelectronic department of Valenciennes University, focusing on health monitoring of aeronautic structures using elastic guided waves and multi-array piezoelectric transducers. Since 2011, he is a Professor in the same department and teacher at the engineering school ENSIAME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sofiane Ghenna</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/ghenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 15:53:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/ghenna/</guid>
      <description>  Assistant professor, UPHF Valenciennes, France   Sofiane Ghenna received the Ph.D degree in electrical engineering from Lille University, France, in 2016. After one year as Temporary Teaching and Research Assistant at Lille University, and two years as Post-Doctoral researcher at CentraleSupélec, Paris, He is currentlly assistant professor at UPHF Valenciennes, France. His research interests include design, modeling and control of smart materials based actuators
 Email: sofiane.ghenna@uphf.fr Social networks: linkedin  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbara Mazzolai</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/mazzolai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 12:35:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/pages/people/mazzolai/</guid>
      <description>Senior Researcher Tenured, Principal Investigator, Center Coordinator   Barbara Mazzolai is Director of the Center for Micro-BioRobotics since February 16th, 2011, and she was Deputy Director for the Supervision and Organization of the IIT Centers Network from July 2012 to 2017.
She graduated (MSc) in Biology (with Honours) at the University of Pisa, Italy, in 1995, and received the Ph.D. in Microsystem Engineering from the University of Rome Tor Vergata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twinnims Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.twinnims.eu/news/twinnims-kick-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 13:06:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.twinnims.eu/news/twinnims-kick-off/</guid>
      <description>The launch meeting takes place on November the 21st, 2019 in Sheraton Amsterdam Airport Hotel &amp;amp; Conference Center, room Frankfurt, Amsterdam.
  Twinnims Kick-Off Meeting, Amsterdam
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>